Guide to the Joe David Bellamy Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Joe David Bellamy papers
1962-2014
YCAL MSS 610
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
62.11
(79 boxes)
The collection consists of correspondence, research and writing files, production files, audiocassettes, professional papers, printed material, a computer disk, and other papers, documenting Bellamy's work as an author and editor, as director of the Literature Program of the National Endowment for the Arts, and as editor and publisher of Fiction International magazine.
Bellamy, Joe David, 1941-2014
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Ralph B. Sipper on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund and the Sinclair Lewis Fund, 2000-2007, and gift of Joe David Bellamy, 2014.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 48, 76 (audiocassettes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 77, 79 (born digital): Restricted fragile material. Reference copy of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Associated Materials
Books from the Bellamy collection are cataloged separately, with their provenance traced.
Joe David Bellamy
Joe David Bellamy was born in Cincinnati, Ohio in 1941. He attended Duke University, Antioch College, and the University of Iowa Writers' Workshop. He is the author of the novel Suzi Sinzinnati and the collection of stories Atomic Love in addition to other works. He was the founding editor and publisher of Fiction International magazine and press. He served as director of the literary program of the National Endowment for the Arts from 1990 to 1992.
Further biographical information can be found on the author's website: http://joedavidbellamy.com/.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, research and writing files, production files, audiocassettes, professional papers, printed material and other papers, documenting Bellamy's work as an author and editor, as director of the Literature Program of the National Endowment for the Arts, and as editor and publisher of Fiction International magazine.
Arrangement
Organized into four groupings: I. June 2000 Acquisition. II. August 2006 Acquisition. III. October 2007 Acquisition. IV. May 2014 Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time.
Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with and/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. For instance, writings can be found in all three groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Researchers should also note that similar material can be arranged differently in each acquisition, depending on how the material was organized when it was received by the library.
Fiction International; American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Editors -- United States -- 20th Century; Fiction -- Periodicals; Poetry -- Periodicals; Audiocassettes; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Editors -- United States -- 20th Century; Bellamy, Joe David, 1941-2014; National Endowment for the Arts. Literature Program
- June 2000 Acquisition, 1967-2000; 1; 44.13; (55 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This portion of the collection contains correspondence, research files, audiocassettes, and other papers related to Joe David Bellamy, the National Endowment for the Arts, The Falcon Magazine and other magazines and organizations.
  Arrangement
  Organized into two subgroupings: Correspondence, and Writing, Editorial, and Project Files.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 48 (audiocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  General note
  Formerly classed as: Uncat MSS 63
  - Correspondence
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
    - Abbott, Lee K, 1980-1991 (Box 1)
    - Adams, Alice, 1983 December 23 (Box 1)
    - Ai, 1980 June 25 (Box 1)
    - Alberts, Laurie, 1981-1997; 2 (Box 1)
    - Anaya, Rudolfo, 1979 July 28 (Box 1)
    - Angell, Roger, 1979 April 23 (Box 1)
    - Apple, Max, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
    - Ardizzone, Tony, 1985-1990 (Box 1)
    - Atwood, Margaret, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
    - Auster, Paul, 1985 January 8 (Box 1)
    - Baber, Asa, 1967-1993 (Box 1)
    - Banks, Russell, 1973-1993; 2 (Box 1)
    - Baraka, Amiri, 1980-1985 (Box 1)
    - Barber, Phyllis, 1981-1992; 2 (Box 1)
    - Barrett, Andrea, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Barth, John, 1971-1980 (Box 1)
    - Barthelme, Frederick, 1978-1988 (Box 1)
    - Barthelme, Steve, no year April 26 (Box 1)
    - Baumbach, Jonathan, 1972-1980 (Box 1)
    - Bausch, Richard, 1988 April - May (Box 1)
    - Beattie, Ann, 1977-1980 (Box 1)
    - Bell, Madison Smartt, 1991 February 2 (Box 1)
    - Bell, Marvin, 1972-1992 (Box 1)
    - Bellow, Saul, 1991 August 1 (Box 1)
    - Benedict, Dianne, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
    - Benedict, Elizabeth, 1981-1992 (Box 1)
    - Benedikt, Michael, 1973-1984 (Box 1)
    - Blaise, Clark, 1974-1983 (Box 1)
    - Bly, Robert, 1970-1988 (Box 2)
    - Boles, Robert, 1969-1974 (Box 2)
    - Bourjaily, Vance, 1970-1995 (Box 2)
    - Boyle Symposium, 1995 September 28-30 (Box 2)
    - Boyle, T. Coraghessan, 1976-1999; 3 (Box 2)
    - Bradley, David, 1984 February 1 (Box 2)
    - Brooks, Gwendolyn, 1980-1984 (Box 2)
    - Brown, Rosellen, 1974-1979 (Box 2)
    - Brownstein, Michael, 1976 October 12 (Box 2)
    - Burkard, Michael, 1974 May 10 (Box 2)
    - Burroway, Janet, 1989 March 24 (Box 2)
    - Busch, Frederick, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
    - Carlson, Ron, 1985 January 12 (Box 2)
    - Carruth, Hayden, 1988 December 17 (Box 2)
    - Carver, Raymond, 1979-1981 (Box 2)
    - Casey, John, 1973, undated (Box 2)
    - Cedering Fox, Siv, 1973-1991 (Box 2)
    - Charyn, Jerome, 1985 January 9 (Box 2)
    - Cherry, Kelly, 1973-1998; 3 (Box 2)
    - Cheuse, Alan, 1977-1990 (Box 2)
    - Chiarella, Tom, 1983-1993 (Box 2)
    - Ciardi, John, 1970 July 20 (Box 2)
    - Colwin, Laurie, 1983-1985 (Box 2)
    - Conroy, Frank, 1992-1999 (Box 2)
    - Cox, Elizabeth, 1980-1994 (Box 2)
    - Creeley, Robert, 1978 September 24 (Box 2)
    - Dana, Robert, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Daniels, Kate, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
    - Delbanco, Nicholas, 1988-1992 (Box 2)
    - Derricotte, Toi, 1991 March 30 (Box 2)
    - Dickey, James, 1970 October 12 (Box 2)
    - Digges, Deborah, no year November 22 (Box 2)
    - Dillard, Annie, 1977-1981 (Box 2)
    - Dixon, Stephen, 1974 February 24 (Box 2)
    - Dobyns, Stephen, 1971 August 1 (Box 2)
    - Doctorow, E.L., 1983 (Box 2)
    - Dodd, Susan, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
    - Doig, Ivan, 1985 January 8 (Box 2)
    - Elkin, Stanley, 1980 May 30 (Box 2)
    - Engle, Paul, 1979 December (Box 2)
    - Eshleman, Clayton, 1975-1991 (Box 3)
    - Eugenides, Jeffrey, 1989 December 22 (Box 3)
    - Exley, Frederick, 1979-1988 (Box 3)
    - Federman, Raymond, 1972-1985 (Box 3)
    - Forche, Carolyn, 1979-1993 (Box 3)
    - Ford, Richard, 1988, undated (Box 3)
    - Furman, Laura, 1977-1990 (Box 3)
    - Gallagher, Tess, 1975-1995 (Box 3)
    - Gardner, John, 1982 May 26 (Box 3)
    - Garrett, George, 1987 January 5 (Box 3)
    - Gass, William H., 1981 November 21 (Box 3)
    - Gerald, John Bart, 1976-1984 (Box 3)
    - Gerber, Merill Joan, 1991-1996 (Box 3)
    - Gildner, Gary, 1973-1980 (Box 3)
    - Gish, Jen, 1982 October 28 (Box 3)
    - Godwin, Gail, 1975-1979 (Box 3)
    - Greenberg, Alvin, 1974-1984 (Box 3)
    - Grumbach, Doris, 1980-1986 (Box 3)
    - Gurganus, Allan, 1985 January 8 (Box 3)
    - Hall, Donald, 1989-1993 (Box 3)
    - Halpern, Daniel, 1980 Jan 24 (Box 3)
    - Harnack, Curtis, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
    - Harper, Michael S., 1981-1984 (Box 3)
    - Hawkes, John, 1975-1986 (Box 3)
    - Hegi, Ursula, 1977-1980 (Box 3)
    - Henderson, Bill, 1978-1998; 3 (Box 3)
    - Hijuelos, Oscar, 1984 January 7 (Box 3)
    - Hirshfield, Jane, 1990 December 7 (Box 3)
    - Hribal, C.J., 1988 April 22 (Box 3)
    - Huddle, David, 1990 October 16 (Box 3)
    - Hugo, Richard, 1978 November 8 (Box 3)
    - Humphreys, Josephine, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
    - Irving, John, 1982-1992 (Box 3)
    - Judson, Jerome, 1989-1991 (Box 3)
    - Johnson, Charles, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
    - Jong, Erica, 1974 June 22 (Box 3)
    - Justice, Donald, 1978 September 8 (Box 3)
    - Kaplan, Bernard, 1970-1980 (Box 3)
    - Kinnell, Galway, 1979-1982 (Box 3)
    - Kittredge, William, 1971-1973 (Box 3)
    - Klappert, Peter, 1984-1988 (Box 3)
    - Kostelanetz, Richard, 1973-1991 (Box 3)
    - Kumin, Maxine, 1970-1974 (Box 3)
    - Kunitz, Stanley, 1978 (Box 3)
    - Laughlin, James, 1973-1980 (Box 3)
    - Lawrence, Seymour, 1974-1980 (Box 3)
    - Leavitt, David, 1985 January 8 (Box 3)
    - Lee, Li-Young, 1991, undated (Box 3)
    - Levertov, Denise, 1978 November 27 (Box 3)
    - Levine, Philip, 1984 May 4 (Box 3)
    - L'Heureux, John, 1979-1985 (Box 3)
    - Lish, Gordon, 1973-1989 (Box 3)
    - Livesey, Margot, undated (Box 3)
    - Long, David, 1976-1984 (Box 3)
    - Lowry, Beverly, 1987 December 4 (Box 3)
    - Ludvigson, Susan, 1991-1992 (Box 4)
    - Macauley, Robie, 1975-1985 (Box 4)
    - McCloy, Kristin, 1989 (Box 4)
    - McMillan, Ian, undated (Box 4)
    - McMillan, Terry, undated (Box 4)
    - McPherson, Sandra, 1991 November 1 (Box 4)
    - Madden, David, 1972-1981; 2 (Box 4)
    - Major, Clarence, 1975-1977 (Box 4)
    - Mason, Bobbie Ann, 1974-1990 (Box 4)
    - Matthews, William, 1974-1979 (Box 4)
    - Meredith, William, 1976-79 (Box 4)
    - Miles, Josephine, 1980 June 25 (Box 4)
    - Millman, Lawrence, 1981-1982, undated (Box 4)
    - Minot, Susan, 1981-1991 (Box 4)
    - Mirsky, Mark, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
    - Moore, Lorrie, 1977-1999; 3 (Box 4)
    - Morgan, Frederick, 1976-1980 (Box 4)
    - Morris, Wright, 1966 November 17 (Box 4)
    - Morrow, Bradford, 1991 (Box 4)
    - Mukherjee, Bharati, 1981 October 27 (Box 4)
    - Myers, Jack, 1983 February 17 (Box 4)
    - Naslund, Sena Jeter, 1983 November 30 (Box 4)
    - Naylor, Gloria, 1985 January 9 (Box 4)
    - Newman, Charles, 1974-1985 (Box 4)
    - Nova, Craig, 1984 January 8 (Box 4)
    - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1971-1993; 5 (Box 4)
    - Ochester, Ed, 1989-1993 (Box 4)
    - O'Connor, Philip F., 1992 January 13 (Box 5)
    - Olson, Toby, 1985 January 7 (Box 5)
    - Phillips, Joyce Anne, 1977-1988; 3 (Box 5)
    - Plumly, Stanley, 1993, undated (Box 5)
    - Poverman, Charles, 1973-1979; 2 (Box 5)
    - Price, Reynolds, 1967-1994 (Box 5)
    - Price, Richard, 1981 August 16 (Box 5)
    - Ray, David, 1969-1971 (Box 5)
    - Rector, Liam, 1991 (Box 5)
    - Reed, Ishmael, 1977-1992 (Box 5)
    - Rich, Adrienne, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Robison, Mary, 1987 November 18 (Box 5)
    - Ryan, Michael, 1976-1978 (Box 5)
    - Sadoff, Ira, 1971-1976 (Box 5)
    - Sarton, May, 1980 February 10 (Box 5)
    - Schultz, Philip, 1966-1972 (Box 5)
    - Schwartz, Lynne Sharon, 1985 January 8 (Box 5)
    - See, Carolyn, 1996-1999 (Box 5)
    - Serling, Rod, 1962-1967 (Box 5)
    - Shacochis, Bob, 1983 February 9 (Box 5)
    - Sheed, Wilfred, 1983 August 27 (Box 5)
    - Shields, David, 1985-1987 (Box 5)
    - Silko, Leslie Marmon, 1979 December 10 (Box 5)
    - Simic, Charles, 1978 September 8 (Box 5)
    - Simmons, Charles, 1979 February 7 (Box 5)
    - Siyahi, Carol, 1974-1975 (Box 5)
    - Sloan, James Park, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
    - Snodgrass, W.D., 1978 (Box 5)
    - Snyder, Gary, 1978 September 8 (Box 5)
    - Sontag, Susan, 1972-1979; 3 (Box 5)
    - Sorrentino, Gilbert, 1980 March 21 (Box 5)
    - Soto, Gary, 1992 June 3 (Box 5)
    - Spark, Debra, 1988-1989 (Box 5)
    - Spires, Elizabeth, 1979 January 28 (Box 5)
    - Stafford, William, 1970-1978 (Box 5)
    - Starbuck, George, 1969-1980 (Box 5)
    - Strand, Mark, 1978, undated (Box 5)
    - Stitt, Peter, 1981 October 8 (Box 5)
    - Sukenick, Ronald, 1972-1980 (Box 5)
    - Swan, Gladys, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
    - Tate, James, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
    - Taylor, Henry, 1991 (Box 5)
    - Thompson, Jean, 1974-1980 (Box 5)
    - Thompson, Jeanie, 1992 March 16 (Box 5)
    - Tillinghast, Richard, 1981 December 22 (Box 5)
    - Turco, Lewis, 1992 January 29 (Box 5)
    - Updike, John, 1976-1992 (Box 5)
    - Villanueva, Alma Luz, 1982-1991; 3 (Box 6)
    - Voigt, Ellen Bryant, 1975 December 17 (Box 6)
    - Wagoner, David, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
    - Wakefield, Dan, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
    - Wakoski, Diane, 1973-1985 (Box 6)
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 1986-1987 (Box 6)
    - Weaver, Gordon, 1973-1980 (Box 6)
    - Weingarten, Roger, 1981, undated (Box 6)
    - West, Paul, 1975-1985 (Box 6)
    - Wier, Dara, 1981-1990 (Box 6)
    - Wiggins, Marianne, 1981-1991 (Box 6)
    - Wilbur, Richard, 1978-1991 (Box 6)
    - Williams, Joy, 1980, undated (Box 7)
    - Williams, Miller, 1970-1992 (Box 7)
    - Williams, Thomas, 1976-1980 (Box 7)
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1971 January 26 (Box 7)
    - Wilson, Robley, 1973-1983 (Box 7)
    - Wolfe, Tom, 1972-1988 (Box 7)
    - Wolff, Tobias, 1982-1988 (Box 7)
    - Wolitzer, Hilma, 1980-1981 (Box 7)
    - Wright, James, 1978 September 8 (Box 7)
    - Zacharias, Lee, 1979-1981 (Box 7)
    - Zimmer, Paul, 1989-1991 (Box 7)
    - Unsorted letters, 1976-1996; 2 (Box 7)
  - Writing, Editorial, and Project Files
    - American Poetry Observed, galley
    - Superfiction, or the American Story Transformed, author's proof, 1975 May 27 (Box 7)
    - Atomic Love, author's proof, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Droll and Murderous Visions (Introduction by Joe David Bellamy), proof, 1975 January; 3 (Box 7)
    - The New Fiction, proof, 1974 August (Box 7)
    - American Poetry Observed: Poets on Their Work, proof, 1984; 4 (Box 7)
    - Interviews with authors; "poetry checklists", 1979-1981 (Box 7)
    - Interviews with authors, undated (Box 8)
    - Interviews with authors (continued), 1970, undated; 3 (Box 8)
    - Fiction samples (various authors), undated (Box 8)
    - Interviews with Susan Sontag (by JBD) and Jerzy Kosinski (not by JBD), 1971, undated (Box 8)
    - The New Fiction, page proofs, 1974 (Box 8)
    - Letters regarding American Poetry Now; reprint requests, 1972-1982; 2 (Box 8)
    - Reprint requests; page proofs for The Frozen Sea, 1978; 1988 (Box 8)
    - Notices for literary contests, 1987-1988 (Box 8)
    - Literary magazine flyers; clippings, 1987-1990 (Box 8)
    - The Frozen Sea, proofs and clippings, 1988; 4 (Box 8)
    - American Poetry Observed, galley proofs
    - Literary Luxuries, proofs, 1996; 4 (Box 8)
    - Poetry Now: magazine
    - Literary Luxuries, bound proof, [1994?] (Box 8)
    - Suzi Sinzinnati, bound original working copy, undated (Box 9)
    - Writers conference registration forms; flyers for Tom Wolfe's The Purple Decades (intro by Joe David Bellamy), 1974-1982 (Box 9)
    - Able, Baker, Charlie, Dog and Other Stories by Stephanie Vaughn, proof, 1988 (Box 9)
    - Back-cover photographs of various authors, undated (Box 9)
    - Literary Network News, 1993-1998 (Box 9)
    - Publishers Weekly; GEO, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
    - Esquire; Saturday Review, 1981-1990 (Box 9)
    - Publishers Weekly; Book; Time, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Tom Wolfe magazine clips, 1965-1982; 2 (Box 9)
    - Galley proof of introduction to Wolfe's The Purple Decades
    - The Purple Decades, galley proofs
    - Fiction International: letters, brochures, 1974-1982 (Box 9)
    - National Endowment for the Arts: newspaper clippings, letters, 1973-1992 (Box 9)
    - Literary conference brochures, 1991-1992 (Box 9)
    - NEA summer seminars for teachers, 1983-1992 (Box 9)
    - NEA-related letters to Joe David Bellamy, 1990-1993; 6 (Box 9)
    - Literary event brochures, 1989-1992 (Box 10)
    - NEA-related letters to Joe David Bellamy, 1991-1992; 9 (Box 10)
    - Letters regarding advertisements; literary magazines, 1973-1983 (Box 10)
    - Short story and novel queries, 1979-1981; 2 (Box 10)
    - Business letters; literary event notices, [circa 1970-1980]; 4 (Box 10)
    - Business letters; literary event notices (continued), [circa 1970-1980] (Box 11)
    - Small Press Distribution catalog, 1992 (Box 11)
    - Paperback books: Superfiction (ed. Joe David Bellamy) and Lorrie Moore, Self-Help, 1975; 1986 (Box 11)
    - NEA Challenge Overview Policy Panel agenda, 1991 April 3-4 (Box 11)
    - NEA correspondence; censorship "talking points", 1991-1992 (Box 11)
    - Invitations, letters of support; newspaper clippings on NEA, Joe David Bellamy, 1987-1992 (Box 11)
    - NEA-related letters, newspaper clippings, most not regarding Joe David Bellamy, 1991-1992 (Box 11)
    - NEA event announcements, 1987-1992 (Box 11)
    - Memo regarding new legislation, 1990 October 30 (Box 11)
    - NEA newspaper clippings, job announcements, press release on Joe David Bellamy's appointment to NEA, 1990 (Box 11)
    - NEA packet on intergovernmental mobility, addressed to Joe David Bellamy, 1990 July 27 (Box 11)
    - NEA newspaper clippings, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Newspaper clippings on obscenity, 1990; 4 (Box 11)
    - NEA Application Guidelines book, 1992 (Box 11)
    - Poetry Society of America newsletter; Tri-Country Arts Council booklet, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Literature Program kudos, undated (Box 11)
    - NEA-staff, undated (Box 11)
    - NEA newspaper clippings, some regarding censorship; biography of John Frohnmayer, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Clippings on NEA controversy, Frohnmayer writings and speech text, 1991 (Box 11)
    - Guide to the NEA, 1990 January (Box 12)
    - AWP Chronicle; Rocky Mountain Book Publishers Association catalog, 1991-1992 (Box 12)
    - Various western US literary organization pamphlets, 1990-1991 (Box 12)
    - Oryx Press catalog; literary newsletters, 1991-92 (Box 12)
    - NEA application guidelines; Georgia Review article, photocopied, 1981; 1993 (Box 12)
    - AWP Chronicle; press release on Joe David Bellamy's appointment to NEA; Literary Network newsletter, 1990-1993 (Box 12)
    - Small Press Distribution, Inc. catalog, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Vox magazine media kit, 1991 June 13 (Box 12)
    - NEA meeting minutes, review of Frohnmayer autobiography, 1990-1993 (Box 13)
    - Poets and Writers (4 copies), 1991 January-February; 2 (Box 13)
    - AWP newsletters, with newspaper clippings attached, 1991-1992 (Box 13)
    - Frohnmayer speeches and letters; Joe David Bellamy speech, 1990-1992 (Box 13)
    - Publishers Weekly magazines; Literary Network newsletter; Congressional report on NEA, 1991-1993 (Box 13)
    - NEA newspaper clippings; Literary Network News, 1992-93 (Box 13)
    - NEA memos, newspaper clippings, 1990-1992; 6 (Box 13)
    - Report on The Literature Program prepared for NEA; Writer's Center Carousel; A Temple of Texts: Fifty Literary Pillars, 1984-1991 (Box 13)
    - Publishers Weekly: magazine, 1991 May 10 (Box 13)
    - Lila Wallace Reader's Digest Fund literature, 1992 May 7 (Box 13)
    - Report on the American Writers' Conference; NPQ magazine, 1981-1992 (Box 13)
    - Text of the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities Act of 1965, amended December 22, 1987; NEA report Economic Impact of Arts and Cultural Institutions, 1981-1987 (Box 13)
    - Laing Research Services Survey of Independent Presses; NEA application guidelines, 1989-1993 (Box 13)
    - Historically Black Colleges and Universities, report of first national conference for arts faculty and staff, 1989 February 9 (Box 13)
    - Report from Presidential Task Force on the Arts and Humanities; NEA report on education of professional artists and arts educators, 1978-1981 (Box 13)
    - The AWP Official Guide to Writing Programs, 1990 (Box 13)
    - The State of the Arts at State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges, 1979 (Box 14)
    - Supporting the Arts: An International Comparative Study, 1985 (Box 14)
    - Report to Congress on NEA, 1990 September (Box 14)
    - John Frohnmayer Commencement Address, University of Oregon Law School, 1991 May 16 (Box 14)
    - English/Language Arts: Model Curriculum Standards, The Book Publishing Annual, 1985 (Box 14)
    - NEA Memos, newspaper clippings, 1987-1990 (Box 14)
    - NEA application guidelines, press release, memos, 1992-1993 (Box 14)
    - Report on 1984-85 survey of English programs, report on similar 1986 survey, advertisement for NEA program "The Legacy of American Poetry", 1987-1990 (Box 14)
    - NEA memos, various literary newsletters, 1984-1992 (Box 14)
    - NEA memos, NEA-related newspaper clippings, 1991-1992 (Box 14)
    - Poetry Committee meeting agendas, newspaper clippings, 1990-1992 (Box 14)
    - NEA memos, other memos regarding Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCU) events, 1981-1988 (Box 14)
    - Frank Conroy letters, 1982-1983 (Box 14)
    - NEA letters regarding grant applications, 1984-1989 (Box 14)
    - Letters to Frank Conroy, regarding NEA grants, 1984-1985 (Box 14)
    - NEA correspondence, 1983-1988 (Box 14)
    - Resumes and cover letters, 1979-1988 (Box 14)
    - Letters from grant recipients, Prose Fellowship meeting program, 1975-1990 (Box 14)
    - Anthony S. Keller, Contemporary European Arts Support Systems, 1980 June 23-25 (Box 14)
    - Cultural Trends 1990 (photocopy) Publishers Weekly, memo to Joe David Bellamy, 1990-1992 (Box 14)
    - The Canada Council, Arts Councils in Conflict, 1988 June (Box 14)
    - Canada Council information, 1989-1991 (Box 14)
    - Ontario Arts Council annual report and guide to grants, 1988-1989 (Box 14)
    - Information on international (mostly Swedish and Finnish) literary programs, 1988-1992; 3 (Box 14)
    - Letter to Joe David Bellamy from Tom Wolfe
    - AWP business - Denver meeting, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Miami meeting plans, undated (Box 15)
    - AWP convention, 1985-1989, undated (Box 15)
    - AWP budgets, 1990 (Box 15)
    - AWP correspondence, 1990 (Box 15)
    - AWP publications, 1989 (Box 15)
    - AWP, 1990; 2 (Box 15)
    - AWP fundraising, 1989-1990 (Box 15)
    - AWP publications, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Board meeting, 1989-1990 (Box 15)
    - AWP agreements; AWP Chronicle, 1977-1994 (Box 15)
    - AWP Chronicle, 1989-1998; 6 (Box 15)
    - AWP Chronicle (continued), 1989-1998; 3 (Box 16)
    - AWP addresses and labels, 1990-1993 (Box 16)
    - AWP Board of Directors Manual, 1992 (Box 16)
    - AWP Staff Manual, fund raising report, 1988-1989 (Box 16)
    - Legal Assistants, 1976-1977 (Box 16)
    - Associated Writing Programs, 1978 January 6 (Box 16)
    - AWP staff, 1991 (Box 16)
    - Denver meeting minutes, Joe David Bellamy correspondence regarding AWP, 1990-1991 (Box 16)
    - AWP memos, newspaper clippings, 1989-1990; 6 (Box 16)
    - AWP correspondence, Philadelphia conference programs, 1989 (Box 16)
    - AWP Board Manual, clippings, memos, 1988-1989 (Box 16)
    - AWP newsletters, conference programs, 1981-1994 (Box 17)
    - NEA-related newspaper clippings, 1990 (Box 17)
    - Newspaper clippings, most on Cincinnati Mapplethorpe controversy, 1990; 5 (Box 17)
    - Letters to Joe David Bellamy, AWP pamphlets, 1982-1995 (Box 17)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1990 (Box 17)
    - The AWP Catalogue of Writing Programs, 1984; 2 (Box 17)
    - The AWP Official Guide to Writing Programs, 1990-1991 (Box 17)
    - Brochure for AWP conference in Norfolk, 1993 March 25 (Box 17)
    - Coordinating Council of Literary Magazines (CCLM) letters to Joe David Bellamy, 1980; 3 (Box 17)
    - CCLM Memos, 1980 (Box 17)
    - CCLM nomination forms, 1980 (Box 17)
    - CCLM letters to Joe David Bellamy, guide to organizing and exhibiting at book fairs, 1979-1980 (Box 17)
    - CCLM Letters to Joe David Bellamy, 1980 (Box 17)